Michael Jones II

Durham, North Carolina, 27701

Email: <u>mdjones2@protonmail.com</u> | Phone: 919-824-7657

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-jones-ii-5112411b7/

GitHub: https://github.com/mdjonestwo | Portfolio: https://mdjonestwo.github.io/New-Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 7 years of experience in multimedia production, performing arts and gardening who is innovative, adaptable, and collaborative. Great self motivated independent worker and collaborator.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, React **Applications:** VSCode, RoboT3, Postman, Slack, Trello, Terminal, Adobe XD

Projects

Plot of Gold | https://github.com/EddiePhi/Plot-Of-Gold | https://plotofgold.herokuapp.com/

- A gardening app to assist in documenting multiple gardening plots and tracking their progress.
- Designed the UI/UX
- MongoDB, React, Express, Node, Adobe XD

CouchSurf | https://github.com/DustinErwin/CouchSurf | https://dustinerwin.github.io/CouchSurf/

- An organization platform that allows you to see all your favorite apps on a single page.
- Designed and the developed the front end to hold all the widgets
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express

Durham Legends Coloring App | https://github.com/mdjonestwo/Growth Frequency Coloring App | https://mdjonestwo.github.io/Growth Frequency Coloring App/

- Built to let users color in pages from the Durham Legends Coloring Book
- Designed and developed full application
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Express, MongoDB

Related Experience

Author, Illustrator and Publisher

February 2019 - Present Durham, North Carolina

Durham Legends Coloring Book

- Designed a 12 page coloring book to educate the community on local African American contributions
- Distributed over 1500 coloring books to local schools, grocery stores and consumers
- Generated over \$7,000 in revenue by word of mouth and social media marketing

Creative Director and Field Operations Manager

March 2016 - Present

Herban Gardening Collective

Chapel Hill, North Carolina

- Grew over 300 pounds of produce throughout multiple gardening sites
- Created digital promotional materials to educate consumers and increase product sales by 75%
- Taught over 100 students best gardening practices

Performing Musician and Multimedia Producer

Jones Michael

January 2013 - January 2021 Durham, North Carolina

- Recorded 5 EPs, and over 75 records that have over 19,000 streams
- Performed over 100 shows in the United States

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of New Hampshire, Durham, NH A 6 month program focused on creating full stack developers using modern programming languages such as HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express & ReactJS.

Master Gardener Certificate: Durham Cooperative Extension Office, Durham, NC A 6 month program gearing up gardeners to assist local community gardens with knowledge of best gardening practices to maximize yield, deter pests and protect the planet.

High School Diploma: Charles E. Jordan High School, Durham, NC